SARVATH S

DevOps Engineer

- @ sarvathbabu@gmail.com
- in Sarvath
- **→** +91 8870593339
- Chennai, India

- Sarvath
- sarvath.com sarvath-s

SKILLS



Docker **Kubernetes**

Shell scripting **Jenkins**

Terraform Airflow

GitHub Actions Git

GitLab Reactis Jira Recoil Antd

PROJECTS

- Judo Feb'23 to till date
- N-Next May'22 to Jan'23
- ICAPP Feb'21 to Apr'22
- ANB Sep'19 to Oct'20

CERTIFICATION

 Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)

EDUCATION

• BE - CSE St Joseph's College Of Engineering Jul 2015 - Apr 2019

SUMMARY

Overall 4.6 years of experience, including 3.6 years specializing in DevOps, AWS, Azure and 1 year as a ReactJs Developer. Proficient in AWS, CI/CD pipelines, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Shell Script and possess sound knowledge in Ansible.

EXPERIENCE

Software Analyst | Zeptoh Solutions Pvt Ltd.

FEB 2021 - Present

- Chennai, India
- Automated CI/CD pipelines with Git, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Docker, and AWS including writing GitHub workflow files, configuring runners in GitHub Actions, and deploying applications to EC2 instances.
- Provisioned and managed resources using Terraform for AWS (EC2, S3, CloudWatch, SNS) and Azure (VMs, storage accounts).
- Ensured system reliability through proactive monitoring and incident management.
- Administered IAM users, groups, and access keys, ensuring adherence to security best practices through regular key rotation and access management
- Configured and managed EC2 instances, S3 buckets, and security policies for
- Monitored EC2 disk and CPU utilization by creating alarm based on threshold limit using CloudWatch and triggering notification using SNS.
- Utilized Git for version management and Docker private repositories
- Automated deployments with GitHub Webhooks and Jenkins Pipeline.
- Developed UI components using ReactJs and Ant Design (Antd) library; optimized application performance to improve load times and participated in on-call rotations and incident response, ensuring timely resolution of development mode issues.
- Utilized Jira for issue reporting, status updates, and activity reporting.
- Used Python Pandas for data manipulation and analysis by collecting data from IOT
- Implemented Shell Scripting to automate routine system tasks, manage file operations, and streamline deployment processes.
- Managed workflows with Apache Airflow in Contract Lifecycle Management.

Trainee Cloud Engineer | Precision Infomatic Pvt Ltd.

Sep 2019 - Oct 2020

- Chennai, India
- Interacted with clients to track the requirements.
- Had the chance to work with Linux and Windows team and worked on tasks such as monitoring security patches, shell scripting, creating S3 buckets, configuring AWS
- Automated the shutdown of AWS EC2 instances during non-business hours.
- Creating and updating issue in Jira and Itop to track the incidents.